in this problem
we've been given some code on line one
we have a local variable number
that's assigned to a random number
between zero
and nine 9 we want to use our
if statement to check whether the number
is equal to the integer 5
and if it is output the string 5 is a
cool number
otherwise we want to execute the else
clause of our if
statement and output other numbers are
cool too
now the problem description tells us
that currently
5 is a cool number is being printed
every time the program is run
so we need to figure out why and fix our
code
we know that line four of our code in
our if statement
will execute every time the condition we
provided on line three
evaluates as true
so for now let's comment out our if
statement
we'll print the return value of that
code
you can see that the return value of
that code is 5
every time even though the local
variable number in our code
is supposed to be randomly assigned to a
different number between 0 and 9
every time the code is run
[Music]
going back to our code you may notice
that what we're doing on line 3
and therefore what we're providing as a
condition to our if statement
is actually not comparing the local
variable number
for equality to the integer five
what we're doing is reassigning the
local variable number
to the integer five assignment will
always return the assigned value
so in this case we're returning five
every time this code is run
remember that every expression except
for false and nil
evaluates as true in ruby
because we provided variable assignment
as a condition
to our if statement on line 5 that
condition will
always return the integer 5 and
therefore always evaluate as true
and that's why each time we run this
code it outputs 5 as a cool number
what we want to be doing is comparing
the local variable number to 5
and if number is equal to 5
output 5 is a cool number if number is
any other number between 0 and 9
we'll output other numbers are cool too
let's run the code outputting the value
of our local variable number
and then outputting the return value of
comparing number to 5.
so now we're performing the comparison
that we expect
now that we've altered the condition
provided to our if statement
to reflect our intentions let's run our
code
and see if it's behaving as we expect
and it is
so make sure not to use variable
assignment
as a condition for your if statement
it's confusing
and it's likely not what you want